Office (021) 808-4409 Home (021)855-3657

CURRICULUM VITAE of JOHANN TREURNICHT

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

As the result of the various projects and positions I had been involved in since 1978, I have good current capabilities in the following fields:

- Lecturing undergraduate and graduate
- System Engineering
- Software Development
- Computer Design
- Mathematical Analysis and Design
- Control System Analysis and Design
- Integration

CURRENT CONTRIBUTION

Undergraduate: Since 1998 I have presented undergraduate classes in Control Systems, Digital Design Systems and various other courses at the Electrical and Electronic Department, Faculty of Engineering. I have also successfully managed an academic exchange program (USA-RSA) for a number of years.

PostGraduate: I have presented a number of post-graduate courses in Control Systems (pre-dominantly in Robust Control). I have also managed the underwater research and quad rotor aircraft systems in autonomous systems at the Department.

Research: I have given talks at a number of conferences. My current research interest is the flight control of multi-rotor aircraft

Professional Design: I am currently managing the SLADE 2e vehicle at the department. My contribution was to provide a fully funded and well-managed project on which other colleagues and graduate engineers could implement research ideas for advancing the ESL technology. I have been involved with industry to help to solve a number of technical problems, mostly in the field of control systems.

EXPERIENCE

- 1998-PRESENT I am employed by the University of Stellenbosch as a senior lecturer in the Engineering Faculty, Electrical and Electronics Department (computer and control systems group).
 - My lecturing subjects included all the undergraduate control systems courses and robust control post graduate courses.
 - I am also providing engineering consultation to industry with projects ranging from micro-satellite sensor and actuator development to specialized stabilization and control systems for military and other clients. I am currently project manager for the SLADE2e UAV.
- 1995-1998 I was employed by Reumech OMC (now Vickers OMC) as the Engineering Manager for Tracked Armour and later as gun stabilization specialist. During this period I was seconded part of the time to Reunert Defence Logistics (formerly ESD) to help solve gun control problems.
- 1994 -1995 I formed my own close corporation to perform system engineering and analysis consulting work for clients. At this time I was also involved in the Rooivalk bid to the UK.

1978-1994 I started my career at Kentron (Denel Dynamics) and my first task was to provide servos and a power supply from an alternator for a concept RPV vehicle. My second major programme was on design and implementation of the autopilot of a guided missile system.

During the period 1981 to 1982 I studied at Cranfield Institute of Technology, Bedford, England to obtain a MSc. in aerospace engineering.

From 1982 onwards I worked on the concepts, and system engineering of a large mechanized anti-aircraft gun system. I was appointed System Engineer to the 35 mm mechanized anti-aircraft gun system for the definition and development phases of this major development programme.

EMPLOYMENT RECORD

1998-Present I am employed by the University of Stellenbosch.

| 1995-1998 | I was employed by Reumech OMC. |
|-----------|---|
| 1994-1995 | I formed my own close corporation. |
| 1978-1994 | I was employed by Kentron. |
| 1984-1994 | I was part of the Air-defence group at Kentron. |
| 1978-1984 | I was part of the missile electronics group at Kentron. |

QUALIFICATIONS

| 1981-1982 | M Sc Engineering (Aerospace), Cranfield Institute of Technology, Bedford, ENGLAND. |
|-----------|--|
| | My thesis dealt with digital control system design. |

- 1972-1976 Hons B Sc Electronics, University of Stellenbosch. My final project was a communications link to the mainframe computer.
- 1966-1971 Matric Exemption John Orr Technical High School, Johannesburg. My trade subject was radiotricians.

LANGUAGES

I am fluent in Afrikaans and English. My home language is Afrikaans.

PERSONAL

Birthdate 11 December 1953 in Pretoria. I am a South African citizen. My current home address is 24 Topaz street, Emerald View, Somerset West, 7135; of which I am the owner. My home Telephone/Fax number is (021)-855-3657.

I have been married to Henrietta for 35 years and have 3 grown-up children.

EMPLOYMENT STATUS

I am currently employed by the University of Stellenbosch.